1812 Charles St., Raleigh, NC 27610

252-206-6023

mattneal.ncsu@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/m-neal

KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- ✓ Slashed product/supply costs for World of R/C; created and increased margins on branded products from 25% to 85%
- ✓ Quadrupled overall sales for World of R/C to \$1.25M annually
- ✓ Completed an inventory record transfer of 14K+ items into QuickBooks Pro and QuickBooks POS
- ✓ Planned/executed yield research/profit projection improvement projects that generated up to \$5M in additional revenue for Mountaire Farms
- Completed management and leadership development programs

QUALIFICATIONS & SKILLS

Online Order Management & Fulfillment

Purchasing/Procurement

High-Volume Inventory Management

Distributor & Vendor Communications

Workflow Scheduling

Customer Service

Driving Business Expansion & Sales Growth

Strategic Planning

Microsoft Office

Intuit QuickBooks & POS

Professional Photography

Adobe Photography Suite

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Detail-oriented purchasing and inventory management specialist with over six years of experience in operations and financial management. Excels in planning and executing programs and projects that optimize inventory management, slash operating costs, and maximize profits. Provides excellent customer service and drives efficient project completion to exceed production goals.

WORK EXPERIENCE

World of R/C Parts & Supplies, Wilson, NC

Operations Manager, 05/2012 to Present — Ensure operational efficiency by managing inventory, forecasting for optimal cash flow, providing project management leadership, overseeing scheduling and payroll records, and querying daily reports of 10 employees.

- Expand worldwide company reach via internal website, eBay, Amazon.com, and management of contracts with various manufacturers
- Serve as a project manager for on-site events, expos, product demonstrations, and trade shows
- Troubleshoot, document, and test technical product issues for customers; provide technical product training for employees and customers

Impulse Imaging, Raleigh, NC

Owner, 11/2011 to Present – Manage a high-quality photography printing business serving over 100 customers nationwide. Manage in-house inventory and product production, as well as tax and P&L records. Create custom wood frames for clients.

4Fifty8 Acquisitions, Raleigh, NC

Account Manager, 08/2011 to 04/2012 — Applied excellent follow-up and marketing techniques to promote fortune 500 clients, manage B2B sales, secure new business accounts, and ensure client retention. Built high-performing marketing and sales teams by interviewing and training new candidates.

Mountaire Farms of North Carolina, Lumber Bridge, NC

Area Supervisor, 04/2010 to 08/2011 — Oversaw quality production, including management of 50 employees, to produce product for major customers, including Kraft, Sarah Lee, and Boar's Head. Ensured compliance with FDA standards in the highest-demand department.

- Led meetings and conducted training to ensure adherence to safety protocols and quality-control standards; managed HACCP, SSOP, and CAPA documentation
- Calibrated and set up product quality-management equipment for grading, sorting, and density scanning

EDUCATION

BS in Agricultural Business Management, North Carolina State University, 2009 Minor in Economics